houseplans.com 2016-11-29

# Legal & Privacy - Houseplans.com

## Copyright Notice

All house plans listed on this site are protected by U.S. copyright laws. Unauthorized reproduction, sale, or transfer of plan images contained on this site or any other work produced herein is a violation of these laws. These laws allow the copyright holder to recover damages of up to $100,000 per offense. 

Reproducible vellum sets are available for customers who choose to have a local professional customize house plans they have chosen to build. This does not allow the purchaser to build more than one house from a design plan however. 

All content, graphics, and other data stored on this website not expressly stated as being from another source is copyrighted 2016 by Houseplans LLC. ("the owner"). 

All content, graphics, and other data stored on this website expressly stated as being from another source are hereby designated original material, and is the intellectual property of the owner. This material may not be reused in any form, or for any purpose, without the consent of the owner. 

The content of this website may not be reproduced in any form without the express written permission from the owner. It may not be sold for profit or included in any type of archive (commercial or private) without the consent of the owner. Failure to abide by these rules may result in legal action by the owner. Permission is hereby granted to download and view any material for personal, non-commercial purposes and to create hyperlinks to the top level (home page) of this website. 

## Privacy

##### 1\. Overview

This Privacy Policy describes how Houseplans LLC ("we," "us," "our" or “Houseplans”) maintains, uses and shares information that we may collect when you use our websites (the “Sites”) or communicate with us. 

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any such changes will be posted here. If we make a material change in the way we use your information, we will prominently note the change on our Sites. 

Some of the information you provide to us, such as your name, company name, postal address, email address, credit card information or telephone number, may allow you to be identified. We call this kind of information “Personally Identifiable Information.” We may use your Personally Identifiable Information for the purpose of communicating with you, responding to your inquiries, providing service updates, delivering promotions, sending you e-newsletters, and as otherwise detailed below in this Privacy Policy. 

We do not collect, use, or disclose any information about users of our Sites except as described in this Privacy Policy. 

##### 2\. What information we collect and how we use it

**When You Register:** When you register to create an account on one of our Sites, you will be asked to provide your name and email address, along with a password. You will also have the opportunity, but will not be required, to answer certain survey questions (e.g., whether you are a professional builder, when you expect to start your project, and what Zip code you are building in). 

**When You Make a Purchase:** When you make a purchase on any of the Sites, you will need to provide your name, phone number, postal address and the number, expiration date and CCV Code of your credit card. In addition, you may, but are not required to, provide the name of your company. We use this information to fulfill, and communicate with you regarding your order. 

**When You Choose to Provide Information:** We may give you the opportunity to voluntarily provide us with your Personally Identifiable Information and other data for specified purposes. For example, if we receive your permission, we may provide this information to companies for the purpose of marketing products or services that may be of interest to you. 

**When You Respond to Surveys:** We may ask you to complete surveys or opinion polls from time to time. Participation is voluntary. We only use the information that we collect from surveys in an aggregate manner, not in individually identifiable form. 

**When You Provide Your Phone Number:** If you supply us with your telephone number, we may call you with information regarding orders you have placed online. We may also call you about new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such telephone calls, please let us know by sending an email with your name, phone number, and mailing address to us here. 

**When You Make an Inquiry:** If you send us a comment or question or make an inquiry to customer support, we will retain the information that you provide to us for the purpose of responding to your communication, as well as for improving the Sites. 

**When You Make a Blog Posting:** If you submit a comment to a blog or other public forum on a Site, all the information you provide will be available to other users of the forums. We have no control over how others use that information and you should consider this when posting information. 

**When You’re Just Visiting:** If you are just visiting the Sites and not registering, requesting information, making a purchase or contacting us, we do not ordinarily collect any Personally Identifiable Information from you; however, we do collection information from all visitors through web logs, as described below. 

##### 3\. Ways we collection information automatically

**Web Logs:** We maintain web logs that automatically record basic information about everyone who visits the Sites. We use web log information to help us design our Sites, to identify popular features, to improve our services, and for other managerial and analytic purposes. We may also use web logs to help identify someone who may be misusing the Sites. These logs contain: 

  * Your Internet Protocol (IP) address.
  * The type of browser and operating system that you use.
  * The date and time you visited a Site.
  * The pages that you visited on a Site.
  * The address of the website you linked from to get to a Site.

**Cookies:** We use HTML cookies, Flash cookies (also known as Local Shared Objects), web beacons and/or similar technologies to help you navigate the Sites, to allow us to learn how you use the Sites, and to improve the Sites. 

Cookies are text files we place in your computer's browser to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not reveal any Personally Identifiable Information unless you choose to provide this information to us by, for example, registering or making a purchase at our Sites. However, once you choose to provide Personally Identifiable Information to the Sites, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. If you decide not to permit cookies on your computer, this may affect your ability to use the Sites. 

We also use Flash cookies for fraud prevention and other purposes. Flash cookies are small data files that a website stores on your computer. These files may contain information about your online browsing activities and preferences. The Help feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Flash cookies are not stored in the same manner as conventional cookies, and not all browser versions will delete Flash cookies when you clear conventional cookies from your browser. If you wish to block or delete Flash cookies, you should confirm whether your browser version supports this feature. You may also use Adobe’s Flash Player Settings Manager to control how your computer handles Flash cookies. 

**Third Party Cookies:** We sometimes allow other companies to set and read cookies on our Sites. These cookies are used to track the effectiveness of ads, to permit companies to show you ads that are relevant to you and for other purposes. The use of cookies by our partners and service providers is not covered by our Privacy Policy. We do not have access to, or control over, these cookies. 

**Beacons:** We use web beacons alone or in combination with cookies to compile information about how people use our Sites and interact with our emails. Beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your computer, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular Site tied to the beacon, and a description of a Site tied to the beacon. For example, we may place beacons in marketing emails that notify us when you click on a link in the email that directs you to one of our Sites. We use beacons to operate and improve Houseplans’ websites and email communications. 

##### 4\. How we share your information

In addition to the uses described above, we may also disclose Personally Identifiable Information to others under the following circumstances: 

**When You Consent:** If you expressly request, or agree, that we may share Personally Identifiable Information, as in the case of sales of leads, we will do so in the specified manner. 

When we Use Service Providers: We may contract with third party service providers to perform functions for us. These service providers may be given access to the information we collect for the purpose of performing those functions, but they will be contractually bound to maintain the confidentiality of the information and not to use it for any other purpose. 

If We Transfer our Business or Assets: If we were to transfer all or substantially all of our assets to another company, one of the assets we would likely include in the transfer is our database of Personally Identifiable Information. 

When we are Legally Required or in Order to Protect Rights, Persons or Property: 

We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information when we are required to do so by law, regulation or securities exchange requirement, for example in response to a court order or subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency's request or when we believe such disclosure is appropriate to protect our legal rights or to safeguard anyone’s property or safety. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors rights generally, we may not be able to control how your Personally Identifiable Information is treated, transferred, or used. Therefore, you should know that in such event, your Personally Identifiable Information may be treated like any other asset of Houseplans, and sold, transferred or shared with third parties, or used in ways not contemplated or permitted hereunder, without notice to you or your consent. 

##### 5\. How you can manage information we collect

If, at any point after giving us your Personally Identifiable Information, you do not wish to continue to receive additional information or be contacted with updates about our services, or you would like to access your registration information to correct or delete it, please let us know by sending an email with your name, phone number, and mailing address to us here. In the case of our email newsletters, you also may follow the procedures included in the removal instructions in each newsletter, or by updating your Account Preferences. We will endeavor to satisfy such requests within a reasonable time. Note that we may not be able to provide you with our services if we delete your information. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the information we collect is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete and current. 

##### 6\. How We Safeguard Your Information

We maintain all Personally Identifiable Information with physical, electronic, and managerial safeguards to help ensure the security and confidentiality of the data against reasonably foreseeable risks. Security is designed to prevent unauthorized use, access, disclosure, destruction, and changes of data. For example, we restrict access to our computing facilities to individuals identified by management as needing access to perform their jobs. Be aware, however, that, even with reasonable safeguards, there is no way to guarantee the security of data. 

##### 7\. Who May Use The Sites

The Sites are intended for use only by adults. We do not target, or knowingly collect any Personally Identifiable Information from, anyone under the age of 18. 

##### 8\. When You Link to Other Websites

Our Sites include links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from our own. Collection and use of your information on those websites is not governed by this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policies of any websites you visit. 

##### 9\. Our Commitment to Accountability

We are committed to adhering to our Privacy Policy and applicable laws and to making your online experience secure and useful. If you have a question, request, complaint, dispute or concern related to this Privacy Policy, you may send a message by email to PrivacyManager@Houseplans.com or write to us at: Houseplans LLC, Attention: Privacy Manager, 617a 2nd St, Petaluma, CA 94952. We will work with you to obtain a prompt resolution of any issues you may have. 

## Currency

All pricing published on our website are in US Dollars. 

## Pricing

Pricing and conditions subject to change without notice. 

Due to the very large number of plans and price options for those plans offered by Houseplans, data entry and other errors inevitably may occur in the text and pricing shown on this website. Consequently, please be advised that Houseplans reserves the right to correct such errors as they are discovered, and no order and pricing with respect to that order shall be final until confirmed by Houseplans. 

All construction plans ordered through Houseplans.com are provided as-is and Houseplans.com disclaims all other warranties, express or implied, including merchantability or fitness of purpose. The photographs placed online may differ from the actual plans, depending on the modifications performed by the owner/builder. Construction plans may not be returned for credit and/or refund under any circumstances. Houseplans.com is not liable for incidental, special, consequential, or indirect damages of any kind, including, but not limited to, loss of anticipated profits, business opportunity, or other economic loss arising out of the use of services or any construction plans received from Houseplans.com even if Houseplans.com has been advised of the possibility of such damage. It is the customer's responsibility to ensure the accuracy, compliance with applicable statute or regulation, and fitness of purpose of any plans or construction information received from Houseplans.com prior to use thereof. In the event any liability is imposed on Houseplans.com, Houseplans.com's liability to you or any third party shall not exceed the price paid for Houseplans.com's product. 

## Return Policy

All sales on house plans and customization/modifications are final. No refunds or exchanges can be given once your order has started the fulfillment process.
